welcome to episode number 314 of
de numero res grata CCCXIV
category 5 technology TV it's Tuesday
V genus technology TV suus 'Martis
the twenty-fourth of September 2013
ad VIII Kalendas Septembris MMXIII
great to see ya true well we made it
Puer nobis verum etiam ut magno fecit illud,
this far all right yeah hey hey how's it
Nullam consectetur est quam ipsa recte memini talia
going excellent yeah well we have
tam praeclara habemus ad yeah
exciting things coming up how about I
quae est quid de me venire excitando
let you know what's coming up in the
quid suus 'venient in te
newsroom good one yeah so the iphone 5s
Gaudete et bona NewsRoom iphone 5s
touch ID was hacked within days of
Id autem in die caedere tactus
launch so like that fingerprint you know
et sicut scitis quod launch fingerprints
the hacked bad news iphone um HP is
et delinquentibus nolite malum hoc nuntium iphone um HP
stalking ubuntu powered laptops in 1500
stalking powered Laptops in Ubuntu MD
of its stores in china oh happy day for
O beatum Sina enim dies, in sui stores
a beer ah in Hindu is winning and Apple
et conciliandos in Hindu ah dolor sit Lacus
is failing they had that's what I've got
Hoc illud est quod est non habuerunt Ego got
it one little glitch one little glitch
eam unius glitch unius glitch
and you wrote this with a great pride
Scripsit et superbia magna
I'm sure yeah carrying on mmm Oh a new
Im 'certus yeah O novam rem gero mmm
home theater chair vibrates and pulses
sella in domum theatrum inducto venarum vigor et concitavit
in time with your surround sound
cum in Sono circumiecto
interesting you try watch jurassic park
ortus spectare velis jurassic elit
again i think oh yeah valve has
Puto adhuc habet O yeah valvae
announced steamos a linux-based scheme
nuntiatum est steamos Linux ratio fundatur
operating system he's excited stick
operating ratio quod suus 'excitatur lignum unum,
around these stars are coming up later
haec est post stellas circum ecce venient
in the show Oh what else would we got
o spectaculum quod non aliud per nos got
okay tonight for all of you geeks or
noctem universa bene pro geeks aut ex vobis
wannabe geeks so all you Robbie's over
wannabe geeks ut in omnibus Robbie scriptor
there all of you want to be listen up
Sursum autem vis omnis
tonight we're gonna be looking at the
si respiciens in nocte sit amet
linux terminal yes we're gonna be doing
Linux terminalis etiam non facere sit amet
some bash scripting some PHP coding that
vercundus aliquam aliquam scripting, quod coding PHP
is executive all we're going to teach
est exsecutiva docebit omnia, et nos erant 'iens
you all different kinds of things while
rebus omnibus generibus
we're going to start with some basic
erant 'iens ut satus cum basic aliquam
stuff we're gonna get into some more
erant 'agnus dei adepto magis in aliquo supellectilem
advanced stuff we're gonna get into
provectus supellectilem erant 'agnus dei adepto in
multitasking through your boss scripting
multitasking per vestri bulla scripting
so don't go anywhere it's gonna be a lot
et non usquam suus 'agnus dei esse multus
of fun tonight don't worry it's gonna be
suus 'agnus dei esse a fun nocte nolite ergo solliciti esse
I are you know make it funky goes look
Sequitur videre faciam te sumus Carmina
girly yes with girlish glee don't go
ita hilaritas non girly calathosque sinumque
anywhere we'll be right back this is
Haec est recta nos huc
category 5 technology TV
V genus technology TV
at eco alkalines we believe you should
Eco alkalines ad vos, ut credimus,
be able to trust your batteries not just
posse confidunt tua eu gravida, non solum
here but here here and here but with one
sed hic unus hic passim
exception you should also be able to
Item poterit exceptio tibi
trust your batteries here Eco alkalines
Hic habeat fiduciam tua eu gravida Eco alkalines
of the world's first and only certified
mundi primus et solus certified
carbon neutral battery manufactured to
neutrum ipsum fabricari, et ad altilium
the highest standards of recycling and
et signa summa redivivus
quality without any trace amounts of
qualis sine ulla copia
harmful chemicals like mercury lead or
noxia chemicals fluctuat argenti uiui aut plumbum
cadmium eco outlines provide performance
Eco aurantiacis descriptio perficientur providere
the rivals leading national alkaline
ratarum trium alkaline ducens nationalibus
battery brands at a comparable price
altilium brands in simili pretium
find out more about the Eco alkalines
e pluribus invenire Eco de alkalines
difference Eco alkalines calm this is
Eco difference alkalines hoc leniret
category 5 technology TV i'm your host
V genus technology TV sum exercitum tuum,
Robbie Ferguson I'm crystal walls yeah
Robbie Tacitus me uitro parietes yeah
I'm category 5 TV as a member of the
Im 'socius pro TV in V genus
tech podcast network if it stack gets
ipsum si fit acervus Quintus Tech
here and the International Association
huc International Association
of Internet broadcasters awesome hey
Internet broadcasters heus horribilis
check out our mobile website it's mcat
Lorem website est nostra mobilia mcat
five dot TV I have booze and that
Habeo quinque dat TV et booze
medical code or go to mcat 5db you can
aut medici codice mcat 5db ire potes
listen to category 5 TV radio ken how
genus unde scis audire V radio TV
does that work category 5 TV radio will
quod genus operis TV radio V facit voluntatem
call it category 5 technology radio
vocant id genus technology radio V
however less confusing a little less
Sed paulo minus confunderent
confusing though us be like is it TV
Etsi autem conturbat nos, ut non sit TV
you're watching with your ears we're
tu vigilantes sumus enigmata percipite auribus vestris
describing the awesomeness that you're
ibi de illa terror vestri '
seeing if you're watching the TV portion
Si autem cum erant 'vigilo TV est pars
of the show but yeah we've got all that
Comperto autem ostendunt omnia quae de yeah
at em cam 5 TV as well as on-demand
em-at cam V de demanda tum TV
video live video feeds as well check
Vivamus quoque reprehendo video video feeds
that out today get fast I got a book
ut qui hodie ex ieiunium ut libro possedi
from old salt sent to us in the mail
ad veteres conditus in tabellariorum
just wanted to say shouts out his wife
sicut voluit dicere clamat et uxor eius
wrote a book which is something to be
scripsit librum, qui est esse aliquid
really really proud of in gratitude for
cor vere vere in lectulo suo
grace thank you for sending that into us
ut mitterent nobis gratiam pro gratia
old salt and kudos to your wife and
sal et kudos ad senex et uxor tua
congratulations on the book release
Rhodii gratulatum se de librum release
that's awesome so it was good to see I
adeo terribilis videre quod esset bona mea
have been working hard on our new
durum opus sunt nobis novum
transcoders of Christ which for those of
transcoders Christi quae ex illis
you who aren't familiar with what a
quae nota sunt vobis
transcoder is basically when we record a
Nuno autem transcoder cum recordarentur
show we're using encoders to record two
ostende erant 'usura duobus encoders recordarentur
discs and we get one great big what we
discs et dabimus tibi magnum est quod magnum
call the master file it's a huge file
vocant domino 'a lima quod lima ingens
well it's not huge it's one and a half
tam ingens suus 'suus' non unum et dimidium
gigs so it's it's really large then in
sic suus 'gigs suus' realiter tunc in magna
order to get it to you at home
Ut vos adepto ut domi
we have to then take the end coated file
ergo debemus accipere finem file iactaret
and transcode it which is to re-encode
et transcode eam quae est ad re-encode
into a format that is going to be
forma autem in futurum
supported by your device by your
ipse tuo fultus tua fabrica
computer by your television set however
set tamen sem computatrum tua
it is that you're watching so the
hoc est, quod tu sic vigilabo
transcoder server takes that 1.5 gig
1.5 cisiis pervolavit transcoder servo accipit illud
file and converts it to all these other
omnibus his aliisque eius file quoque et proselyti
formats including web m4 html5 streaming
M4 formats inter tela html5 streaming
on our website it's got LD files if
suus 'got lima si nostro loco LD
you're subscribed to the LD feed those
tu autem transeunt ad partes illorum feed LD
are really really tiny versions of the
vere vere minima es in versiones
show like under 60 Meg's in order to
ut ostenderet per LX est scriptor ut Meg
watch the the entire hour got mp3 SD and
et custodia omnis hora accepit D mp3
HD files there as well you'll find them
Youll 'reperio ea est etiam HD files
all at category five dot TV / RSS and
ad omne genus quinque dat TV / and RSS
what's exciting is we're back at
Quid enim sumus tergum procul excitando
transcoding all the old episodes and
transcoding omnia vetera episodes
we're currently averaging about five
de erant 'fere quinque currently
episodes per day wow that's pretty good
TV suus 'pulchellus bonum, quod wow per diem,
so the transcoding server has already
Iam ergo habet servo transcoding
gone back to beyond because it's going
quia ultra reversus deferretur
back in time right so you'll see you
et videbis justum in tempore
know some of the newer episodes are all
sciunt aliquid de novior omnibus online
transcoded some of the older ones are
transcoded senior ones sint de aliquo
still on youtube or maybe blip TV it has
usque in YouTube vel maybe blip autem TV
gotten back to before last Christmas so
Ita Christus ad superiorem evasisse
very very exciting we were working on
opus sumus nimis suscipit
bringing up that average it certainly
admotisque average ut eam certissime
the first this was the first week that
Haec prima sabbati, quae fuit ante
it was up and running so that's going to
et factum est ut suus 'currentem ad
be going out because there was having to
erat enim habens exire
re-encode retrans code files because
rursus, quia encode Retrans codice files
something went wrong or maybe I found
aliquid abiit iniuriam, vel maybe inveni
something that I could have optimized
quod ut potui optimized
with the script so I've done some
Itaque cum legere aliquid feci
tweaking over the past week so five a
et quinque a hebdomadam revolutam per tweaking
day is pretty good though I think it's a
etsi satis puto suus 'a bonum die est
good starting point anyways crits no six
initium boni anyways, non crits sex
a day but well we're working our way I'm
Bene nos iter nostrum ego autem in die laboramus
hoping that this week do you think I can
sperans, quod hoc septimana vobis videtur non possum
do 80 I don't know I think you should
LXXX do vobis ut ego non puto
aim low and then like surprise yourself
te mirari libet intentum et humilis
we're gonna try for three with crystals
sumus agnus dei attentent quia tres sunt ex crystallis
algorithm here what else is exciting
Est aliud quod hie algorithm excitando
about the new transcoder servers it
servers illud de novo transcoder
means that when the show is over tonight
hoc est spectaculum quod est in hac nocte
the episode is going to be available
res autem praesto est iens
through our website category 5 TV
V genus nostrum website in TV
minutes following the broadcast cool
passim minuta post frigus
what so no waiting less than an hour
quod nihil minus quam horam exspectabat
after the show you'll be able to watch
Post spectaculum youll posse vigilate
it on demand through our website then
Tum extemplo in website
the transcoder server starts
et servo incipit transcoder
distributing it through to our RSS feeds
distribuendi illud ad nos RSS
blip TV youtube all those so those are
et omnes illi qui blip TV YouTube
secondary
secundarium
our website will always receive it very
accipientibus semper est website
very quickly so I'm excited about that
sic cito sum concitatae ut
viewers on our website want to
viewers vis in nostro
congratulate Scorpio 55 and slip they
LV CONGRATULOR Scorpionis et lapsus sunt
both hit 250 weeks of watching category
et hebdomades ledo CCL of vigilantes genus
5 TV recently so both of them get a
V TV et tum recens ex eis accipere
bronze crown award which is really cool
qui vere frigus aeris coronam award
kudos for that I'm shiny Raptor 222 and
qui kudos ad CCXXII Ego lucida et raptor
rob treed are just a couple of weeks off
non facias violentiam treed duobus weeks iustus off
so keep watch and actually don't yeah
ita etiam nec memini vigilemus
and then check out your awards on our
Lorem praemia vestrae et nostrae
website category 5 TV also Raptor 222 is
V TV genus website etiam est raptor CCXXII
very close to hitting the 5,000 viewer
Visum percutis proximum 5000
points mark that's huge folks it's huge
mark puncta folks suus 'ut' ingens ingentis
what that is going to do is that's going
Quid autem sit acturus, quod suus 'iens
to get you the coveted silver double
ad te argentum duplex concupivi
dagger award and there's only I think
et non puto illic 'award pugione
seven other people they sound like
sonant aliis septem
really cool Awards I'm just saying yeah
Im 'vere iustus frigus Awards dicens yeah
well think about all the viewers
bene cogitare de omni viewers
category five and only seven other
nisi quinque et septem alii genus
people have this award today I'm a Jake
homines huius award me hodie a Jake
get like a little dagger it's like if ya
ut pugione paulum similis est, si quasi Agnus
on their profile yeah sorry it's not as
Non memini contristatus est super profano
cool as she makes it sound it is coveted
haec enim facit frigus et canetis sit nullius concupivi
though and we congratulate our viewers
et quamquam nostro viewers
for having achieved those and if you are
Nam et si sunt rerum
watching the show tonight you've got a
ostende te in nocte vigilantes possedi
really cool rig and you want to show us
rig realiter frigus, et ostende te nobis est
what it looks like and how it is that
et quod simile sit
you're watching the show hey make sure
heus tu spectaculum spectans fac
you set up a picture camera take a
posuistis cinematographica accipere
picture of yourself watching the show
de te ipso vigilantes in picture show
with your set up and send that our way
sic statuo vestra ut mitteret
Cara it's live at category 5 TV and
V Vivamus TV suus 'apud Caracarum et genus
we'll send you one hundred viewer points
erimus vobis centum punctis inspectoris
for sending that in so that's another
misso in alio ut in
way for you to be able to get I think we
nam via ad adepto posse puto nos
should say hello some of our new viewers
salve novum aliquid dicere nos ex viewers
as well yeah looks like we have a lot
tum yeah vultus amo habemus multum
after this weekend hi eek a mouse okay a
Hi post eek vestibulum mus a purus
mouse well he says it way more fun than
mus non modo plus amet, quam bene dicit
we have announced this week every time
nuntiatum sabbati omni tempore quo fuimus
like that absolutely no how do you like
quod non est omnino simile, quam vis facere
that actually I dating outside you do
dating extra me hercule illo die vos facite
you about the most by connection watch
circa vigiliam circa plurima
the video oh really okay we have
O rem video bene autem non
surveillance in the studio of course we
studio utique in custodia
have a service camera in the new stucco
habent officium ad novum camera polita opere tectorio eleganter
as well monitoring everything that goes
ut omne quod magna
on and I we are working on it right so I
et nos fas est ut opus in
go back in time on a couple of the
in tempore reverteris ad duo
videos to see you know how the progress
ut sciat qualiter ad profectum vestrum videos
yep and sure enough its motion activated
yep satis certus, et motu suo activated
so lo and behold the first video that i
quod ego video, ut prima ecce lo
click on there's a mouse scampering
illic 'a mus click in discursu
along and the rabbit yeah just checking
Iustus reprehendo, et per cuniculum yeah
things out so so set a humane trap we're
profecti igitur sunt de sic animus humanus captionem sumus
going to release them somewhere it wears
ibant autem in quodam loco wears dimittere eos
up maybe your front yard good no just
maybe sunt vestra bona non solum hortum
somewhere safe yeah it's very nice like
tutus loco memini sicut pulchrum est
he'll be well cared for lucky mouse yep
quod te felicem esse matricibus sane custoditis mus yep
moving on oh noes i said to carry you
Quis ferat ad reptile et Noes
elias alias carry elias I yes that
Elias quidem in alias feras et Helias
sounds more logical yeah hey Ervin
Multo est probabilius, altum yeah heus Ervin
sadhus commute yeah you should probably
yeah sadhus commutatio, non ut verisimile
tried hackles up no I'll let you keep
nil ego servabo te examina hackles
that one Ervin so Tosca welcome I'm very
Puccini unam Ervin excipite itaque me ipsum
very sorry crying all right who else we
Qui contristatus clamor aliud iure
got a hangar race nice to have you
nisi vos a stirpe sublatum Hangar
joining us jawad jawad hey welcome to
gratissimum nobis placet ut heus Jawad Jawad
rock which is kind of like Tuvok in his
in genere sicut petra Tuvok
teenage years when he was had the spiky
teenage annis, et cum esset cum spicea
hair to match the spiky years to rock
et caput inserere spicea annis quem stabam
Tuvok she's so illogical magics on Star
Tuvok ita convenit ipsa est stella ex magicas
Trek reference yes that's right on yes
Trek ut referat ita iustum est, quod sic
you're back you're right yeah that's all
reversus es tu iustum ut 'omnis yeah
I need to know it's nothing will fix her
EGO postulo scio suus 'nihil et figere eius
yet folks know okay who's after to rock
post quem stabam ut bene quis folks nondum cognoscetis
ah NAT naggy nagy 999 hey welcome to the
ah NAT naggy grata est heu nagy CMXCIX
show Darryl 100ms ghee miss Suzuki
Suzuki darryl 100ms ghee ostendere deferretur
welcome to the show too many consonants
welcome ad spectaculum etiam plures consonantes
my own valve my oath a new Sebastian
valvae juramento mea meus novi Sebastianus
Anders marvelous meerkat welcome said JM
Anders mirifice grata Meerkat dicitur definition | JM
cassia k it really hard names in here I
casiæ autem difficile rem k per nomina hic
think you do this on purpose don't ya
Hoc enim non puto tibi ya
jots been registering uh please good
iotis, obsecro, uh bonum est perscriptum
let's see if we can stump them be Zed II
videamus, si possumus stump sint II Zed
Claire X FN and thank you for this one I
X Claire FN et Wisi enim ad hoc unum mihi
can wrap up with San greets to our
cum alter dicit esse nostras Sancti
latest registrant on our website Peter
tardus registrant nostro loco Petri
see Oh how's it tough welcome to the
vide quid est hoc, o lenta grata est
show
ostende
we're gonna get an email from I say no
Non sumus agnus dei adepto an inscriptio dicunt de me
it's Peter yeah the one word and get it
Et pervenit verbum ad unam Petri suus 'yeah
right man you did it wrong that's how it
quem iustum fecit iniuriam id factum quam
goes yeah thanks for registering on our
memini nomina nostra est gratia
website category 5 TV we love how many
V TV diligamus quot genus website
as a part of our community it's
quia civitas est pars nostra,
absolutely free and you can join just by
absolute libera et iusta ab iungere potest
going to triple w category 5 TV you want
Latin triplici V ad genus vis TV
to thank also our viewers who have
et gratias ago, qui nostros ad viewers
donated this week be it toward just
Hoc septimana ad illum datum est iustus
paying our bills keeping the show going
solvente nostra observatio spectaculum iturus laoreet
and even with the upcoming renovation
nec non et renovationis Spiritus proxime venturos
we're very very excited about all of the
nos omnes valde concitatae
things as we approach it more exciting
quae suscipit magis acceditur
because I'm starting to see things
quia Ego incipiens ad haec
coming to fruition we're about to start
venit ad fruitio sumus ut satus
season 7 next week tonight if you
VII sabbati proximo suo si hac nocte
complete with our sixth anniversary show
anno sexto perfectum ostende nobis
tonight tonight is it oh I'm audit and
O me audit, et hac nocte hac nocte est,
you're here I feel so special so there
Te sunt hic sentio ut peculiari
you go if you can believe we've been on
Si vos potestis credere in habuimus
the air for six years and next week is
altera autem septem annis et sex caeli
gonna be our seventh season opener Wow
Curabitur tempus opener Septimum amet
so everything is just getting so
et omne quod iustus questus est
exciting and and really looking forward
et vere excitando et exspecto
to the things that are to come thank you
in rebus, quae ad gratias ago tibi,
to everyone who's been soaring
ut omnis qui suus esse sidera lapsae
appreciate it muchly mm-hmm so how you
bene sit tibi et quomodo muchly mm hmm,
been oh good and stuff mm-hmm no not too
nec non et materia Mmm mm fuisse O
much just been trying to do a lot of
est iustus conatur facere multum nimis
catch-up on work and I love ketchup
capere-sursum in opere diligamus et ketchup
mustard and yeah everything's about food
Gaudete et omnia est grano cibi
with me yeah things are getting back to
yeah quae sunt mecum, ut recepto
normal yeah good stuff I mean it will
yeah bonum sit normalis supellectilem et non erit
catch up from the time off from the
de tempore adsequi
wedding and yes yeah yeah get it right
et etiam adepto ius nuptiarum yeah yeah
there get it back to speed normal life
ubi pervenit ad velocitatem A normalis vitae
you know what I'm working on right now
quid tibi nunc Im 'opus in
that is is really really exciting what's
hoc est vere excitando est vere id quod suus '
that to me because I am a program I've
quod progressio a me, quia ego sum: quia commune aut inmundum
been I've been developing my own content
Ego esse contentus esse developing mea
management system for some time okay yes
procuratio ratio ita bene aliquamdiu
loving loving loving jquery and ajax and
Nulla et amantes amantes amandi atque Aiaci
and really getting into not just the
et vere, non iustus questus in
server side stuff but doing the client
Servo saepe partem perficere huius
side as well doing the the nice ajax
Maecenas tincidunt in parte operis
kind of work right so getting kind of
ut quando genus operis recta
sophisticated with the backend and and
et cum sophisticated et backend
just the programming you're not so just
ita iustus es non iustus programming
kiddin no i'm not i just remember i'm
Im 'non kiddin non recordabor ego iustus sum
just a town yeah i just i have sheets in
In dui enim ego memini me iuxta oppidum
front of me and i just type in what they
ego iustus typus in conspectu oculorum meorum, et quæ sunt,
give me to tighten and other people do
ut mihi et aliis facere obstringere
the same and then they can't
idem non habent
conglomerated all together
omnes simul conglomerated
and it makes a code yeah mm-hmm doesn't
et non fecerit codice yeah mm hmm,
really work that way no but as a
sed revera non est ita ut non opus
programmer and with the way that things
programmator et omnia quæ in via
change let's see if we can fix that
mutata videamus, si possumus, ut fix
microphone sorry folks there we go are
contristati estis ad tortor ligula, facilisis folks ibi
we all better let's see if that's better
omne enim bonum videamus si suus 'melior
folks check one two as a programmer
fit ut duo programmator reprehendo
though in a real working environment and
quamquam et substantialiter operantes environment
always you know day after day I'm
tu nosti de die in diem semper me
programming a lot of what I what I learn
quod ego multum Aliquam libero quam discite
is just from you know from at this point
scio te in hac parte est a
just doing right so getting yeah so
et rectum est iustus questus Yeah
jQuery has always been there and Ajax
jQuery est et semper fuisse non Aiaci
has been there for a long time and so to
atque ita diu est ibi
to really be diving into it with some
vere tribuo ut sit apud quosdam in illam
really advanced stuff has been a lot of
vere provectus fuit multum supellectilem
fun so folks how how the microphone is
et quo modo amet tortor ligula, facilisis sit folks
doing now okay John says that
nunc facis, qui bene dicit Iohannes
everything's good now I'm guessing that
Nunc Im 'coniciens accidisse quod omne bonum
well that's unpleasant sorry about that
Bene ut 'me paenitet quod triste miscendum
got to get nip that in the bud that'll
nip, quae surrexit ut in semine quod tibi placet
be our season 7 task to figure out
VII esse nostri temporis negotium ut instar sicco
what's been going on with the mic their
Quid agatur in Mic eorum fuit
turn my head how's that do you guys hear
in quo et vos guys, quae turn caput meum audiat
can you face that way just talk about
tu faciem sicut loqui illuc
way the Restless yeah okay I have to do
Sic yeah vivacissimus facere bene habeo,
this well guys turn right now though
Etsi autem hoc quoque guys dextram
right yeah the better guess yeah sounds
yeah recte coniecto yeah sonos in melius
good yeah sounds good now just stay like
bonum autem maneat qualis sonat sicut bonum yeah
that all right so speaking of
et loquebatur de illo omnibus fas
programming tonight we're gonna have
hac nocte sumus agnus dei habere programming
some fun in the linux terminal I thought
aliquid fun in terminos cogitavi Linux
it'd be a lot of fun and I think you're
illa youd 'exsisto multus of fun et ego puto te esse
going to find it the same if you're not
Si vestri 'non iens ut idem illud
a programmer it's okay there this is
bene illic est quod suus 'a programmer
something that you're going to be using
quid erant 'iens ut te usura
if you're on linux you're going to love
Si vestri 'iens ut te amem in Linux
just playing around and learning your
sicut et doctrina vestra circum ludere
way through doing some of this stuff
Per huius operis materia
tonight we're gonna start with some of
satus cum nocte ut quidam amet
the basics we're going to get into
ad basics erant 'iens impetro in
multitasking in the linux terminal so
In Linux, ut terminatio multitasking
actually multitasking your terminal
actually multitasking terminus vester
application and then also developing a
tum etiam applicationem ad developing
PHP script that is going to be executive
PHP script est iens ut esse exsecutivam
from within terminal all right so let's
Recte itaque est terminus intrinsecus
bring up I'm going to bring up my
Eo bring up to bring up my
computer screen here and Krista is going
ad computatrum screen est hic et fautorum
to be utterly amazed at the things that
quae omnino miratus
we're about to learn and yes we're gonna
ut discat, et quod sic sumus nos amet
just hear her saying oh that's awesome
tantum audi dicentem sibi oh ut 'terribilis
yeah so that when everybody watches back
ut rursus cum quisque considerat Yeah
at this if you like wow that girl
si ad hoc, quod puella tibi wow
sitting there is really interested in
sedens est vere interested in
the things that is being taught
quae non est doceri
see such bar so high now I did okay you
videantur quae nunc princeps bar ut bene fecistis vobis
guys just get into it then ok you ready
Bene ergo paratus est intrare guys
take a nap all right here we go folks
hic nos omnes populo OBDORMISCO
hello to the chat room it's so good to
salve in chat cubiculum quod suus 'bonus est
see ya as I nudgee aside okay we're
Puer videre quod bene deponere nudgee sumus
going to go into our terminal I'm going
'iens ut terminus nostra in Eo
to jump onto my desktop that's how I do
onto desktop quod ut salire mihi quid faciam tibi
it I'm gonna make a directory called
Im 'agnus dei esse dicuntur faceret Directory
script with a capital S watch what
quod scriptum capitali Watch
happens when i hit enter thanks Krista
Cum intrabit ledo fit agens Imagines fautorum
there it is Wow alrighty much should I
ut non tantum ibi sit Wow alrighty
doubt well that's that's a little
quin etiam id quod parum
ridiculous alibi cool but at least just
alibi, sed certe frigus risu dignum iustum
you know there's Chyna can try to to
suus esse potest experiri scias Chyna
make it seem interesting hey why's that
Nullam elit id quod non esse
oh thank you thank you okay so bash is
O gratias ago tibi okay ut sit vercundus
basically you know here we are in the
plerumque scio sumus hic in
linux terminal and we want to create a
Linux terminalibus nos volo ut creare
code so what we're going to do is go
codice ita quod erant 'iens ut facere
nan-oh which is the editor that i've
O quam Ego autem nan-Editor est
installed you can install that by going
installed, quod vos can install eundo
sudo apt-get install nano enter your
ut install Nano intra sudo oris sui,
password and you'll see I've already got
Ego password quod youll 'animadverto iam got
it it's the latest version so nano as my
quod suus 'tam tardus poema sicut Nano
text editor or you can use pluma orgy at
text emendator orgia vel vos can utor a pluma
it if you want but we're going to do
sed si te erant 'iens ut facere
everything in the terminal today just
quae hodie sicut in terminalis
for kicks so I'm going to go and let's
et calcibus et sic Im 'iens ut lets'
create our first file let's create
primum lima lets 'partum partum nostrorum
something to actually let's just call it
quod etiam lets 'iustus appellant
our test dot SH file alright so the
Licuit ergo test file dat nobis SH
first thing that we need to do when
Primum est, quod opus quod facere
we're scripting a an application script
erant autem scripting scriptor an application
in Linux is we need to do a well what
Quid enim tam opus est ut faciam in Linux
what was it that William Hung did what
Quid enim feci et quid William Hung
was it hey I actually could not I cannot
heus te enim poterat esse non possum
help you out with this one she bangs she
auxilium vobis cum ea bangs huic illa
bought out Swilley am home okay
ego emit in domum suam bene de Swilley
alright so we need a she bang there it
licet non sit ita necessarium ut ibi bang
is that's what that is it's a hash bang
quod suus 'a Nullam id quod est bang
or a number sign and an explanation
vel plurium rationem signum
point for the novices alright so we've
Ive 'sic licet absolvere possint ad designandum
done that and we go slash bin bash and
et fecit nos et VULNUS bin Pagina
that just tells it okay let's bang the
qui narrat illum solum CREPITUS est ad bene sit
first two character says okay the next
Bene dicit rationem sequenti prima
thing is telling us what our interpreter
est vera interpres, id est nobis,
is and we're going to run a bash script
quod et nos erant 'iens ut bash currere est scriptor
so for this script we can do anything we
sic enim scriptum est enim possumus aliquid
can go echo hello and then we can save
Salve resonare potest salvare deinde
that file with ctrl Oh in in this
o, quod accidit in lima ex hoc
application nano and then exit when
et exitus application Nano cum
we've created a script I'm actually
si youve 'partum a script ego sum
going to move that into my folder
in eo acturum folder
because I just noticed i put that on my
quia ego iustus animadvertit, hoc mihi
desktop so i'm going to go MV is move 10
desktop sic Im 'iens ut MV erit movere X
sh2 and what do they call the folder
et quid ipsi SH2 folder
script in there yeah there we go CD
yeah ibi est in litteras ad CD
script there it is so test SH but you'll
sic enim scriptum test est SH suam ut revertantur illuc
see if I do an LS dash al that it is not
si quid unquam offendas ad al ut video, non est LS
executive all there's my test SH file
Omnia mihi in test exsecutiva illic 'file SH
and it is just read write and then read
Et factum est sicut legitur scribere et legere
read so what I want to do is chmod plus
legi sic, quod plus volo facere chmod
X test SH now you'll see that it is
X SH test youll 'animadverto ut nunc est,
executive all the X bit is set so if I
omnis X exsecutiva frenum est ut si constitutus
go dot slash test SH it's going to
ad apicem VULNUS test SH suus 'iens
execute an echo hello so dot slash means
Salve igitur resiliens per judicium dat VULNUS
current folder test SH is the name of my
SH test current folder est nomen meum,
executive Oh script and there we go so
O exsecutiva ire et legere poterat ibi
let's bring it back up to start editing
obsecro ut satus emendo reduc
that script which we've now created as
qui litteras quas iam diximus creata est
executive all and we do all kinds of
omnia genera facimus exsecutiva
neat things what I'm going to actually
Im 'iens ut vere tersus res quæ
do tonight is we're going to bring up
non enim erant 'iens nocte consurgens adducere
our demo server which is demoed there we
demo nostra servo qui demoed ibi
go demo cat5 TV / 0 16 and you'll see
demo CAT5 ad TV / 0 XVI quod youll 'animadverto
Krista that I've stuck a couple of
Krista quod Ego a duobus adhæsit
pictures in there these are you and I
In his enim estis et imaginibus
actually from I think episode number 30
Numerus res actu a cogitare et XXX
50 so great a photos yeah just a couple
L tanto yeah iustus a duobus photos
of pictures here there we go okay so
hic est de imaginibus ita bene imus,
you'll see that the photos are quite
satis photos quod video te esse
large and that's what I wanted 5.5 Meg's
Et quid suus 'magnum esse volui 5.5 Meg scriptor
to megs three megs and so on so if I
usque adeo ut si Megs Megs tribus
copy the link location of one of those
effingo link loco unius ex illis
files let's go back to our script and
files legere poterant, et eamus ad nos
we're going to go we're going to use W
erant 'iens ut erant' iens ut W
get to grab that file w get
capto, quod ad w file possidebit
and we're going to paste in the name of
et nos erant 'iens ut crustulum in nomine Domini
the file so what that script would now
tabella modo sic, quod si hoc legere
do is it would just grab that file to
iustus lima ut esset capto, ut sit facere
the current folder so if I exit and I
et si quispiam egredi et in current folder
run that script dot slash test Sh you'll
ut scriptor test run dat VULNUS II youll
see that it's actually started
vident ut suus 'iam ingressus
downloading that file so now if I look
quod ita nunc aspicio file downloads
at the folder I've got my script but
Ego in folder autem scriptor obtinuit me
I've also got the the file that i just
Ego quoque surrexit ut in tabella ego iustus
downloaded using my script okay so i'm
downloaded me per litteras ut Im 'okay
going to delete that so some of the
de quo ad delete
things that we're covering tonight are
quae erant in covering hac nocte
just going to be proof of concept and
iustus iens futurus, et probationem conceptu
i'll just say some it may not be you
Ego ibo sicut quidam dicunt, non erit tibi hoc
know i'm not showing you how to write a
Im 'ostendo vos quam ut scribere non scitis
particular script giving you some very
hoc scriptum tibi valde
basic samples of how you know the
quomodo scire basic genera
mindset behind creating something that
et quod post partum questae
you can grow into whatever you want it
si vis potes excrescere
to do that's where things get fun is
ubi res adepto facere quod fun est
when you get creative and you start
Quando vos adepto partum et incipere
creating inventing so i'm going to copy
Im 'iens ut effingo partum sic inveniendi
each of the file names go back into my
per nomina ire in tabella
script and we can w get the next one and
ut possimus audire et tunc unus Latin
then w get the next one and so on and so
Latin sic ut inde postero die et unus
forth w get the next one
ut huiusmodi w proximo
and luckily i have only put five photos
et quinque tantum fortuna i imaginibus
in here so it's not gonna take too long
hic, non ita longum amet
to do this okay there we go haven't
ad hoc bene imus, quia non sunt
duplicated any that's good one of the
decursu duplicata omni bono quod est unum
things i want to do just for the sake of
Iustus volo ut propter
this demonstration you wouldn't want to
huius demonstrationem tu non vis
do this in a real working environment
hoc substantialiter operantes environment
i'm going to actually cap off the speed
Im 'iens ut cap off cursu actually
of w get the reason for that is we're
ut ratio ipsius w, quae est enim sumus
going to get into some examples tonight
'iens impetro aliqua exempla in hac nocte
that i want you to be able to compare
ecce ego ad vos, quia non potest conparari
apples to apples and if my internet is
apples and iubebit poma dari, si sit penitus meum
super fast for one download and super
Super fast download Et pro Super
slow for the next for whatever reason
Deinde ratione tardus
maybe because of the feed or whatever
sive quia fortasse pascuntur
that would give you an apples to oranges
Aurantia poma dare quod
scenario because it might look like it's
illud propter missionem viderem
faster but it's actually the internet
sed suus 'etiam factam, penitus citius
speed fluctuating so we're going to hard
fluctuatur celeritate sic erant 'iens ut durum
set our internet speed on w yet we're
set tamen nostri sumus penitus celeritas in Latin
going to do that with dash dash limit
impetu erumpunt in fine facturus est
dash rate equals 200 k that's going to
CC k aequalis rate de latibulis surrexissent, quod suus 'iens
limit the download speed to 200 kilobits
circumscribere download celeritate ad CC kilobits
per second i'm going to copy and paste
per secundam Im 'iens ut effingo quod crustulum
that over and over again to each w get
et super quod super iterum ad adepto se Latin
command there we go and so what we've
mandatum est itur et quod Ive '
effectively done is we've created a
factum est autem revera creamos
script that says okay i'm going to grab
Im 'iens ut dicit scriptum ut bene capto
these five files i'm going to do it and
Im 'iens ut facere et illa quinque files
i'm going to limit it to two hundred k
Im 'iens ut appellant eamque k ducenti
per second and we're only doing that for
, et per alterum quod erant 'non faciens
the sake of the example so with w get
ita ut exempli causa w
there's a couple things we can do one of
illic 'a duobus faciunt unum omnia possumus
the things i want to do is output the
quae volo facere in output
file name so we'll just call this file
sic tibi nominis file iustus lima hanc
1.jpg we'll call this one as dash oh and
O quantum est de latibulis surrexissent, et si tibi hanc 1.jpg
its capital o not a zero that's for
O caput ejus, non sit nulla ut est
output file dash 0 3 dot jpg the reason
0 III de latibulis surrexissent output lima ratio dat jpg
I'm doing this is so that we can run
Ego sum facis, ut possimus hæc enim curram
this script multiple times we're not
Non hoc scriptum plures temporibus sumus
going to get multiple copies of the
'iens impetro multiple copies
files it's instead going to overwrite 1
lima quod overwrite suus 'iens pro I
2 3 4 and 5 jpg so before I run this
II III IV V, et in conspectu sic curro quod jpg
script because we know it's going to
quia scimus suus 'iens scriptor
take a little bit of time because it
ut paulum temporis, quod
we've limited the speed let's actually
Sit celeritas actu weve 'limited
make it so that our script tells us how
scriptum sit: ut narrat
long the execution takes so that we've
ut longe fiat executio habuimus
got something to compare to so here
quod hic surrexit comparamus, ut
tonight what I'll do is I'm going to
Quid enim mihi hac nocte Im 'iens ut faciam
just set a really really simple timer
set tantum a vere simplex vere timer
way I can do that is i'll create a start
possum te facere ego creo a via ut satus
time of notice what i'm doing here and
notitiam tempus quis ego sum facis huc
i'm going to explain this date
Im 'iens ut hoc explicare diem
and then + % s there okay so you see
non ita bene +% s et videtis
that that particular it's kind of like
praesertim quod eiusdem generis
an apostrophe but it's pointed from the
sed suus 'a dictum pulmenta culinae Prodigus
top left to the bottom right that's just
egressus est summo iure imo quod suus 'iustus
under your escape key on your keyboard
tua effugium clavis ad tua tincidunt
and what that's telling it is okay start
et quid suus 'vera est, ut bene sit initium
is the variable that we're creating then
quae tunc erant partum sit variabilis
that particular character says okay
Bene autem dicitur indole
we're executing this command so we're
et nos sumus exequendo imperium
not actually creating a variable that
non quidem creando, ut variabilis
contains date + % ass we're creating a
Asinus habet diem% + erant creando
variable that contains the output of
qui continet De output in variabilis
that command so if I actually exit this
quia hoc mandatum ut si quispiam egredi actually
I've saved if I exit and I type that
Ego si quispiam egredi et salvus quod typus
date + % ass that's what we're doing is
Hoc illud est quod facis est asinus% + date erant
we're creating a unix timestamp for the
erant enim creando unix timestamp
actual time at that very moment if i run
eadem hora si cucurrero praesentiam
it again it's now gone up by six seconds
suus iam iterum in secundis sex
ok so we're creating a variable that
sic erant 'ok ut variabilis creando
contains the unix timestamp and it's
et factum est cum indicatione temporis habet unix
called start so now that the end of the
unde dicitur quod finis principium
script we're going to create another
'iens creo scriptum est alius
variable we're going to call this end
iens ut id varius
we're going to do exactly the same thing
erant 'iens ut prorsus idem facere
date + % s ' and then end the command
+ date% s et postea in summum imperium
and then we need to do a comparative so
et opus non est ut plures comparative
we've got these two things so when the
Itaque duo Comperto
script started running the script and
currit script et coepi scriptor
then when the script ended this is how
cumque conpleti sic scriptum
we can't i'm a script in a very very
Non sum hoc scriptum non per ipsum
easy way so now we're going to go echo
ita facile ad echo iens
dollar sign and minus dollars pardon me
minus veniam pupa pupa signum
and minus dollar signs start notice the
et minus animadverto pupa signa in incipere
brackets the dollar sign of the
_sed pupa signum
beginning that's telling us to actually
Quod suus 'vera beginning nos actually
execute this mathematical equation and
aequationem interficiam mathematicas
then it will actually output how many
tum voluntate actu quot output
seconds it takes in order to run this
secundus est ut run is
particular script and then we'll go echo
ut youll 'ire et legere poterat maxime resonare
done okay so if all goes well I'm going
Bene ego bene feci sic
to I've saved that control oh and now
Ego, ut salvus esse, et nunc heu
I'm going to run that script again dot
Im 'iens currunt, quod dot iterum scriptor
slash test SH and you'll see it's going
exacuere vade test SH quod youll 'animadverto ut suus' iens
to start grabbing those files so it's
sic suus 'satus ad grabbing eorum files
grabbing the first one and it's saving
primo et salutaris expoliant
it to one jpg and you'll see that it's
et quod youll 'animadverto suus' unus ut jpg
limited to 200 k so that we're comparing
CC ad k ita ut erant 'limited comparet
apples to apples here when we get our
iubebit poma dari apples ut hic noster quo sumus,
output with regards to the timestamp
Quoad output cum indicatione
that's going to take a couple of moments
ut accipias duo momenta deferretur
in order to download because of the the
ut ob ad download
limit that we've given it so what we've
et dedi illud quod inest nobis qui finis
effectively created here Krista is a
Imagines fautorum ex effectu hie creata est
synchronous a non multitasking script so
a non synchrone agunt et multitasking scriptor
basically it does this it waits it does
basically expectatur quod hoc facit
the next step and it does it it's
tunc step et facit illud suus '
sequential so everything that happens
et omne quod fit sequentem
happens in sequence right so the concept
fit ratione consequenter rectum
that I want to demonstrate tonight is to
quia est vis demonstrabo hac nocte
actually say okay well we're w getting a
bene dicimus etiam tum sumus questus in Latin
whole bunch of files why are we waiting
Quod totum Fasciculumque lima expectamus
for one file to finish before we start
ante satus consummare ut lima pro nobis
the next file we have a multitasking
altera file habemus multitasking
environment why don't we actually
Cur non de facto amet
download them all at the same time okay
Bene omnia simul download
so that's what we're going to show you
ita ut 'quis erant' iens ut ostenderet tibi
still going it's on to 4.jpg so we've
tamen suus 'iens ut 4.jpg sic Ive
got one more looks like we're good Oh
surrexit similis unum sumus, o bona
looks like I've messed up the last line
Ego quasi viator sursum spectat ultima linea
so you notice those 68 seconds is what
ut animadverto quam is qui LXVIII seconds
that took let's check what I did on the
scriptor reprehendo facta feci in
last line five okay let's just kill the
quinto purus est scriptor ultima interficere
last line because it didn't execute all
quia non ultima exequi
right so we know from that test we're
et scimus quia recte a test sumus
going to just going to mark this down it
vide ad iustus iens deorsum
took 68 seconds so one minute and eight
LXVIII tulit unum minute, et octo tam seconds
seconds to run okay so what we can do
ut possimus facere quae bene currere seconds
now is editing that script let's create
Nunc lets 'quod edere partum est scriptor
a multitasking environment within our
et intra ambitum Multitasking
script we're going to make the script
erant 'iens ut scriptum est scriptor
asynchronous in the way that we're gonna
asynchronous in via, nos amet
do that we're going to go the end of the
quia erant 'iens ut faceret in finem
line and we're going to add an ampersand
et nos erant 'iens per line addere ampersand
and that ampersand says okay we're going
et bene dicit quod erant 'iens ampersand
to run the next command at the same time
deinde imperium simul cursu
and we're going to run the next command
et nos erant 'iens currunt iuxta imperium
at the same time and we're going to do
simul sumus facturi
the same one we're going to download all
similiter autem erant 'iens ut download Omnia
four of these files at the same time but
quatuor simul et illorum lima
then here's where you got to think a
et hic est cogitare a quo obtinuit
little bit strategically because all
quia omnis paulum opportuna communitaque
those things are happening at the same
Eodem forte illa
time but what happens now and is going
Quid est autem nunc temporis
to execute and so well if these things
et haec ita facere
happened at the same time and they
autem simul et
happen immediately after start then end
tunc demum fiet mox satus
is going to happen immediately after
mox ventura
start because these things are running
currit satus, quia haec sunt,
asynchronously they're running all at
ipsi erant 'currit omnis asynchronously
the same time multi tasking
Multi etiam tasking
multithreaded and so end is going to be
ita finis futurus multithreaded
less than a second later than start even
minus quam secundam post satus est usque
though these tasks are still executing
Hos tamen officio exequendo
so the way to avoid it jumping straight
recto itinere ut vitare saltare
to the next command before these things
Haec altera contra praeceptum
have finished is we want to use the
nos volo utor is consummavi
command wait and wait says anything that
Insidiatur ut aliquid expectare imperium
is multitasked before this point let's
de his vero quod prius multitasked
wait until those four things have
Donec habent quatuor
completed or however many things it is
consummatum est et quamvis multa
and then we can proceed with the rest of
reliquis deinde procedat
the script so I'm going to save that
ita scriptum Ego praeter
control oh and hit enter and then exit
O ledo control et intraveritis et exitus
and now let's run that script again we
et nunc lets 'run iterum scriptum est nobis
were at sixty sixty eight seconds the
Sexagenarius erat sexaginta octo secundis
first time test SH you'll see that the
quod youll 'animadverto primum test SH
output is a little different because
output paulo diuersum
it's running all of them on top of each
suus 'currentem super se omnes eorum
other all four files downloading at the
altera ad quatuor quaternionibus download
same time we go some of them have
Eodem tempore certo habent
completed
complebitur
and because these are running at the
et quia haec sunt currit ad
same time we're going to be cutting down
et priscum pariter iens
our execution time of the script
poenam nostram scriptionem tempus
exponentially so what's the downfall of
Quid est exponentially in ruinam iniquitas
running them all at the same time there
non omnes simul concurrentibus
you go 28 seconds so we're 40 seconds
XXVIII minutes XL secundis et tu sumus
less I guess you know if you're if
Ego coniecto vos scire, si minus, si vestri '
you're smart about it there's not going
Ibi suus 'non iens ut vestri' captiosus circuitum
to really be a downfall because you're
et quod realiter sint in ruinam iniquitas in te
going to limit how many tasks are
futurum erit negotiatio quot
running at once of course if the tasks
simul currit utique si tasks
are going to be using a lot of CPU power
ut sit potestas ire per multum CPU
you can use top or H top to see how many
te potest uti C summo vertice aut quam multis videre
resources you're putting on your server
opibus ponere es servo tuo
but in this case if I were downloading
et in hoc casu, si cum downloads
say a hundred files asynchronously I'm
dico centum asynchronously sum files
going to be using a lot of bandwidth on
'iens ut uti multus of Sed in est
my internet connection so then I can
et conexio ergo mea non possum
cleverly think okay well I've limited it
tam scite bene me arbitramini Ego dubiis regionibus
to 200 k / stream so between five files
k ad CC / amnis ut inter quinque files
you know that's about a Meg per second
scitis quod est per alterum de Meg
right so with a 120 Meg's download
Meg a dextris et cum CXX download scriptor
service that I have I'm nowhere near my
opera, quae ego habeo nusquam apud me
cap so I'm still good to download
Cap ut bonum et adhuc download
however many file I could be downloading
Ego autem multa possent file downloads
200 files asynchronously and it wouldn't
Et si non asynchronously CC files
max it out so so not a lot of downside
ita ut non sit amet eluuntur max
to it but we wouldn't run too many
sed illi non tot concurrentibus
things asynchronously or multitasking
quae asynchronously et multitasking
because it would use more resources so
quia sic uti copia
28 seconds from 68 seconds multitasking
XXVIII secundis LXVIII multitasking seconds
indeed speeds up the task a lot okay
citato certe negotium multum bene est
because everything's happening at once
omne quod fit statim
so now that we've downloaded the files
sic enim iam ut weve 'downloaded files
asynchronously we've waited now let's ma
Expectavimus asynchronously nos iam lets 'MA
graph I them we learned this a couple of
Quibus cognitis duobus purus sum
shows ago dash resize 640 x 360 star jpg
ago ostendit stellam de latibulis surrexissent resize DCXL x CCCLX jpg
and let's make sure that the case is dot
et faciamus quod certa sit causa dot
jpg lower case that's good and then
causa quod jpg minus bonum et inde
ampersand because we're multitasking and
ampersand multitasking, et quia erant '
we're going to wait so ma graph I is
erant 'iens ut MA ad exspecta me graph est
going to happen and then everything's
et quidquid futurum est
going to execute so what I'm going to do
Quid facturus sum ad faciendam
I'm going to output that file and exit
Im 'iens ut output file: et exitus
to my terminal and I'm going to delete
Im 'iens ut terminus meo, et delere
all of the files that have currently
omnibus qui sunt currently files
downloaded so that we can see this
ut possimus videre quod downloaded
actually happen I'm going to execute
Im 'iens ut serviant mihi accideret
that script which is going to download
quia scriptum est: quae facturus download
all four files at the same time and then
tum simul omnes quatuor quaternionibus
it's going to take those files and it's
suus 'iens accipere illud lima quod suus'
going to resize them with ma graph I to
ad eos resize purus sum ma
a maximum of 640 pixels why
quod maximum elementa DCXL
and 360 pixels high you see if I open
CCCLX et elementa vides, si alta aperire
one right now because I can do that it's
nunc autem quod potest facere quod suus '
3500 by 1969 now it says the image has
Nunc autem dicit imaginis est in MCMLXIX MMMD
been modified because obviously it got
mutata manifesto quoniam pervenit
through the entire process if I reload
si per integrum processum reload
let's wait for it it's still going
exspectamus adhuc scriptor suus
actually so quite a massive image there
satis enim magnum et ipsa imago
it goes ma graph I is taking place and
quod quidem fit ma non purus
if I open it now you'll see it's only
si autem quod youll 'animadverto suus' non aperire
640 x 360 the exact same image so it
DCXL x CCCLX in exactam similiter sic imago
downloaded everything at the same time
downloaded omnia simul
it waited until that download process
tantum moratus quantum illud, quod processum download
was complete because you can't resize it
quia non est perfecta resize
if it hasn't finished downloading yet
si tamen non consummatum downloads
and then once it was finished
et postquam consummata
downloading it resized everything to a
ea quae ad downloads resized
maximum of 360 x or 640 x 360 and then
X x DCXL CCCLX et maximum CCCLX
waited until that was done and then told
et expectavit gestis nuntiatum
me how long it took which was only 31
me quam diu tulit eam quae est tantum XXXI
seconds that's what the script tells me
seconds meam illud est quod narrat scriptor
here on my screen 31 seconds is all that
hic est, qui me screen XXXI seconds
took there it is so that's pretty
tulit inde est, quod suus 'pulchellus
exciting when you realize that you can
quod vos can animadverto si vos excitando
you can actually create scripts that run
, quod actualiter currere vos can partum scriptor
certain commands at the same time
simul quaedam imperia
because a lot of times that's
propter quod multum temporis
advantageous if you're transferring
si commodius tibi competit transferendi
files down and then uploading files at
et tunc uploading lima in files
the same time you can do them all at the
cunctos simul potes
same time you don't have to actually
ut ipse non habeat same time
wait for one process to be complete it's
ut impleatur illud expectare processus
been really really helpful just as a
sicut est vere rem utile est
good example are transcoder server as
exempli gratia servo ut boni sint transcoder
its encoding then the next episode it's
altera res est tum modum translitterandi eius
already uploading the previously encoded
Iam antea discas Encoded
little files right so it's doing all
Parum est igitur omne limis
these things at the same time in the
simul haec in
same way that makes sure that you know
Eodem modo, ut scis, quod planto certus
it's not over taxing the server but it's
suus 'non sunt obiceres in calculonis servi tamen suus'
also getting a lot done in very little
similiter fit amet ipsum
time so that's pretty cool I think so
simul, ut suus 'pulchellus frigus non puto
next step I told you I'd like to take a
dixi tibi velis ad gradum proximum progredi non accipies
look at PHP as well and what we can do
at quod facere potest, et quoque PHP
with that and what's neat about PHP is
et qui in sordibus est, quod circa hoc PHP
you can actually run it a lot of people
te potest multum populus non offendi manifeste,
don't actually know this you can run it
vos can run illud non nescientibus,
as an actual executive ol program
ut per ipsam exsecutiva of progressio
because PHP is again another interpreter
quia adhuc aliud PHP est interpretis sui
so in order to do that watch this we
vigilate itaque quia hoc facere
need a couple of things on our on our
duobus opus sunt nobis ad nostros
computer sudo apt-get install we're
sudo ut install bene sumus computatrum-
going to need PHP 5 dash CLI
V unquam offendas ad opus PHP cli
which is command line interface now I've
quod nunc mi order versus interface
already got the newest version so I'm
ita Im 'iam got newest poema poematis
good to go all right because we're
bonum ad omnes, quia recte sumus
working with grabbing files off of the
cum rapies in off opus files
server I'm also going to want something
Im 'iens ut volo aliquid et servo
called curl and curl is a tool that
Crispum et vocavit Crispum, quod est instrumentum
allows me to transfer files from outside
sino mihi ad transferendum a foris files
server safely and get the data from
ut a tutus quod servo data sunt
another server so in this case we're
ita aliud in hoc casu servo sumus
going to actually pull data from demo
notitia ad ipsum trahere e demo
cat5 TV / 0 16 and so I want to use the
CAT5 TV / 0 XVI et volo utor
curl tool in order to do that so I'm
facere instrumentum ut Crispum et ego
going to go sudo apt-get install and
sudo ut install bene ire, et
we're going to need I'm not sure if we
Im 'non certus si nos erant' iens ut postulo
needed curl itself we probably could use
uti posse probabiliter nos ipsum opus Crispum
it but php5 dash curl will likely
hoc autem verisimile nisi Crispum de latibulis surrexissent php5
install that as well there you go and
et ire ut install etiam ibi
again I've already got the newest
Ego iterum iam obtinuit novissimâ concinne︡
version installed so I'm good to go but
versio installed, sic Im 'non bonum ut
i want to show you those steps so that
ut illa steps ut vos volo ostendere
you know that that that's necessary so
tu scis quod ne id quod est necessarium
now that I've got php5 CLI installed I
surrexit php5 installed Ego sum, quod nunc cli
can go where is PHP and hit enter that's
ledo possit exire et intrare ut 'ubi hoc PHP
going to tell me where my PHP executive
Ad dic mihi quo exsecutiva PHP
Liz which is user bin PHP we're going to
Liz user bin qua erant 'iens ut PHP
need that for our interpreter so nano
et quia opus nostrum Torcimanum sive Interpretem Nano
test dot PHP and watch what's different
PHP apicem quid aliter expertus et vigilate
here we're not going to start our PHP
hic erant 'non iens ut satus nostri PHP
file like that we're gonna instead do
qui erant quasi pro non file agnus
what's a call she bangs she bangs ok and
Quod suus ok bangs et vocatio illa quae bangs
it was user bin PHP so that is going to
Disputatio futurum erat ut bin PHP
become our interpreter so now i can go
interpres, ita ut ego potest modo facti sunt
PHP and i can use PHP commands to go
PHP iubet ire utor PHP
dollar sign christa equals hello yeah
Yeah salve pupa signa pares Christa
now i can go echo dollar sign christa
signo nunc Christa pupa potest imago
output that exit and remember what we
qui memini, et quod exit output
need to do because it's a script if i do
si feceris, quod postulo suus 'scriptum faciam
LS dash al it shows me that it is not
LS latibulis surrexissent et al ostendit mihi est
executive also i'm going to go chmod
Im 'iens ut etiam exsecutiva chmod
plus x test dot PHP and then dot slash
deinde plus X amet apicem dot VULNUS PHP
test dot PHP when i execute that what
cum fecero quod dat amet PHP
did it do it actually output it the
faciam hoc et illud esse output cum eo
value of the string christa which is
valorem filum de qua Christa
hello so you see that we're actually
Salve, ut videtis, quod vere sumus
executing PHP code as an executive all
PHP codice ut impleatis omnia exsecutiva
script
scriptor
that's awesome especially when we
quod cum maxime terribilis
consider okay if we look at this this is
si bene consideretur haec intueri
the index of these files at / 0 16 on
cum indice ad harum files / 0 XVI die
demo cat5 TV and feel free to do exactly
demo CAT5 TV et sentire liberum prorsus ut faciam
what i'm showing you tonight if you want
quis ego sum si vis showing hac nocte
to learn how to do this kind of really
discere autem quomodo facere huiusmodi realiter
cool stuff we're going to use curl to
frigus supellectilem erant 'iens ut ad Crispum
get the file list we're going to take a
ut erant 'iens ut album in a lima
break for the news and then we're going
nuntium et conteram enim erant 'iens
to come back and I'm going to actually
Im 'iens ut adveho et actually
load through PHP we're going to get the
onus per PHP erant 'iens impetro in
list of files from the server so that I
ita ut servo lima in a album
don't have to manually copy and paste
effingo quod crustulum nec have ut manually
the file names we're going to create an
partum a lima nomen erant 'iens ut esse
array based on the output of Apache
secundum ad output de Apache ordinata
there with the list of the file names
cum lima nomen in album de
and we're going to run the exact same
et nos erant 'iens currunt, iisdem
thing we're going to download those
eas res erant 'iens ut download
files with W get we're going to do it
cum erant 'iens ut facere adepto W files
asynchronously and we're going to modify
et nos erant 'iens mutare asynchronously
it all automatically generated instead
illud statim pro generatae
of instead of us having to code it
et pro nobis ad Codicis habens ea
manually good stuff that's cool this is
manually supellectilem bonum quod est frigus
category 5 technology TV thanks for
V genus technology agens in TV
joining us tonight are you ready oh I
O utinam paratus es hac veniendo
think they're ready all right all right
recte putant recte parati
folks here are the top stories from the
Hic summo sem historias
category five dot TV news room I'm
genus quinque dat cubiculum Im 'TV News
pretty sure Robbie intentionally wanted
satis certo consilio volens Robbie
me to beat this story how I'm gonna do
me beat hoc fabulam quam me laudibus?
yeah
yeah
alright i read it begrudgingly the Apple
licet legit illud I ad begrudgingly Lacus
promotional video says that your
Quisque video inquit tuum
fingerprint is one of the best passwords
Tesserae fingerprints est optimus
in the world the technology within touch
et in tactus technology in mundo
ID is on the most advanced hardware and
Et ligula id est antecedens
software we've put into any device yet
tamen weve prudenter quodcumque in software
within just a few short days of launch
Lorem ex in iustus pauci brevis diebus
the technology has been hacked whoa try
Heus experiri technology quod iam enormiter exeruisset
not to act too excited yes oh we're not
Sed proh dolor non agere et non sumus
talking about your nosy roommate
de tuos contubernalis olfa
accessing your phone by touching it to
ut obvius vestri phone si tetigerint
your finger while you're asleep the hack
dum digito tuo tu somnum hack
is so serious the hacker can access your
grave est, tam in Piratica non potest accedere te
phone with a simple photograph of your
Digital photograph of vestri phone cum a simplex
fingerprint has taken from your glass a
fingerprints ex vobis est in speculo
group known as the Chaos Computer Club
Chaos Computer Club quae coetus
demonstrated that a fingerprint of the
demonstrandum est, quod per fingerprints
phone user photograph from a glass
illustration from phone user speculo
surface was enough to create a fake
Satis fuit creare fake Superficiem
finger that could unlock an iphone 5s
Digitus posset reserare iPhone 5s
secured would touch ID the photograph of
firmatisque tangeret id scan
the users print was cleaned up inverted
print users ad purgandum erat inversus fuerit,
and laser printed at 1,200 DPI onto a
et laser typis in de 1.200 DPI onto
transparent sheet with a thick toner
transparent sheet cum densissima cartus toner imprimanta
setting then pink latex milk or white
profecta deinde candida puniceo Aliquam lacte
wood glue was smeared into a pattern
gluten in ligno forma inlitum
creating by created by the toner on a
creavit ex creatus est in toner cartus
transparent sheet remove remove from the
transparent removere a sheet sa
transparency a touch that I touch the
quod diaphanum tactu contingere
phones touch ID sensor and presto you're
id sensorem et tange phones es Domine Deus
in that easy hey yeah that's wild it's
qui facile feram quod suus 'heus yeah
like they've used a laser printer as a
ut youve 'adsuesco assuesco a laser sunt quasi printer
form of a 3d printer because yalan you
3D typographus autem propter formam yalan
remember you're on transparencies I used
transparencies ego in te esse memento
to use it with overhead projectors and
sunt supra caput, et sic ut Projectors
stuff and I had a laser printer and
et habens laser printer et supellectilem
that's right the toner is you can feel
cartus toner imprimanta est ut suus 'ius tibi et sentire possunt,
it about so if they then lay out glue
si tunc eam bitumine ponere
and it creates the the actual thumbprint
et per ipsam gignit Thumbprint
what if I just just thinking on top my
ego mihi super hoc iustum putant
head here what if you don't have
hic quod si caput non habent,
fingerprints like what if you
sicut si fingerprints
accidentally have like like a like a
sicut accidens habet sicut tamquam
knife cutting accident or something and
aut accidente aliquid amputatis testiculis et ferro
you just don't have you lost all 10
X Omnes vos habere amisit iustus es non
fingers or you don't have hands and you
Manus habent et non digitis
can't get into your phone but why would
quod autem non potest non adepto in vestri phone esset,
you be using a smartphone without hands
vos potest uti Mauris quis felis absque manibus est
that's really awkward Siri Siri I said
Inconcinnus quod suus 'vere Siri dixi Siri
pizza place pizza place is yeah I don't
locus pizza 'pizza' et non est locus yeah
know how to hard to take that one
scitis quam difficile est accipere, quod
official hands artificial hands that
officialis manus manus ut artificialis
don't have fingerprints yeah I don't
Non ego non yeah fingerprints
think it's a good idea in the first
reputo suus utilem primo
place I mean it seems I hear one thing
hoc loco videtur hoc audiens
they have HP is HP I don't know
HP est HP habent nescio
computers that have it as well though
quamquam is quoque, qui sunt computers
that catch that they've had it for quite
Cape hoc enim satis erat, quod theyve '
a while but that's it's a gimmick and
dum tamen et quod suus 'a gimmick
nobody really uses it not that I could
ita ut non possem realiter nemo adhibet
they track down criminals well here's
scelestos atque ad track descendit hic est
the question is if they have a
quaestio est, si se habere
smartphone an iphone 5s where is their
5 * ubi Mauris quis felis est iphone eorum
fingerprint being stored government so
fingerprints recondita et imperium
yeah is the NSA monitoring every time
memini enim adipiscing tempor NSA
they open their phone as I oh there is
aperiam in eorum phone O quam sit
track of Bobby Ferguson just turned on
semita iusti convertit in Bobby Tacitus
his iPhone and we finally track the guy
ad suum iPhone et tandem track Guido
down that scumbag then they they follow
quae deinde sequuntur usque scumbag
your attack in cahoots with out what
quid tibi cum impetu Cahoots
you're looking at online who knows but
quis scit nisi tu quaeris in online
is it really safe to have that kind of
ita ut vere, ut ex hoc tutum
technology in your phone what happens if
technology in telephonum id fieri si
somebody reverse engineers it and is
et quis avertet eam fabrum
able to read your fingerprint and then
te legere poterat et fingerprints
generate with a laser printer and some
et generate cum laser printer
wood glue something to be able to take
lignum glutine casei aliquid possit accipere
over your life that darn wood glue if
Si lignum glutine darn vitae tuae
you don't have fingerprints to answer
et non ad respondendum fingerprints
your question Heather you just need a
vos iustus postulo a vobis quaestio Heather
laser printer and some make your own
Laser printer et faciet tua
fingerprint that's what you're saying
fingerprints ut 'quod cupis dicere
spiral ones from from a picture of
spiralem de ones de imago Dei
sightings glass just go to the local pub
multae speculum iustus vado ad pub locorum
and get out all the fingerprints you
ex omnibus te atque fingerprints
need there you go I just borrow mine
non opus meum vos faciam sicut mutuari
there you go take a picture of that good
ubi vos take a picture illius bona
thing they're only at 1280 by 720 huh
tu autem est solum per DCCXX huh MCCLXXX
which is fuzzy just fuzzy okay but it
quae quamquam iusta est, quamquam bene autem non
did still work check this out good news
non tamen operatur reprehendo sicco haec tibi evangelizare
for Ubuntu fans oh you're so oh yeah
O utinam tam tui yeah fans in Ubuntu
well for the past week HP has been
bene propter hebdomadam revolutam fuerit HP
stalking to new ubuntu linux laptops in
adspicere dum ad novum in Ubuntu Linux Laptops
over 1,500 of its stores in china the
In Sinis est super 1.500 sui stores
news arrived less than two weeks after
Minus duo weeks post nuntium venit
dell also expanded the number of its
Dell et expanded numerum eius
retail outlets carrying ubuntu devices
retail exitus cogitationes portat Ubuntu
both of HP's latest ubuntu powered
Lorem scriptor HP est tam tardus Ubuntu
offerings are relatively similar in
in se similes sunt
specifications offering intel i3 to i5
cubits offering Intel i3 ad i5
processors 2 gigabytes of ram and
II processors, et pecoris navisve requiro gigantocteti
between 500 gigabytes and one terabyte
et unus inter D gigantocteti terabyte
of hard drive storage space the laptops
laptop coegi repono spatium durum
are available now and start at a price
et nunc praesto sint ad satus price
equal to about 640 canadian dollars
pari ferme DCXL Canadian pupa
I think it's great but when are they
Cum autem magna puto
gonna come to Canada never because I
ad Canada quia non agnus dei
want to see on store shelves and really
volo te videre in copia crusta et realiter
the faculty know the fact well what what
scitis enim quae facultas eo etiam
do people love about Max they love is
et qui se amat amor est circa Jordan
that it I need an awesome computer what
Quid enim opus est, ut computatrum horribilis
you got for me no that's the Apple
et pro me ut 'got Lacus
versus PC argument of the commercials
commercials ratio versus PC
where pc is actually microsoft windows
Microsoft Fenestra PC ubi actualiter
so now you put linux ubuntu with unity
vos modo unitati Decuria Linux
on a computer and say here's great
dicens hic est magnus in una PC
hardware great software for six hundred
sexcentis magna odio Software
forty bucks vs. that macbook that's
id quod nos leones quadraginta Apple
1,700 bucks you know add a thousand
1,700 addere mille illos leones, quos tu nosti
dollars because i know we've all got
scio quia omnia weve 'got dollars
disposable income but honestly what is
PROMPTU reditus sed id quod est in fide
it that we like we like no viruses not
Non amo nos nulla virus
the threat of getting viruses we like
ad periculum questus ut libet virus
stability rock solid nature of the
petra solidum firmitate natura
architecture the fact that it's
quod suus 'architectura
screaming fast and it stays that way
Ita manet eiulare ieiunare
because like mac and linux they are non
quasi Linux, quod Mac, et non sunt,
fragmenting file system so you don't
fragmenting ratio lima ut vestri facio
have to defragment your hard drive
vestri ferreus coegi ad defragment
because they never get fragmented so if
quod si ita redacta sunt ut nusquam
that's why i'm spending 17 hundred
ut 'quare Im' XVII centum spending
dollars on a macbook the app store sure
app store certa de pupa super MacBook
the apps are rich and iTunes is you know
apps quod dives es et tu scis quod iTunes
a pretty popular piece of software
pulchellus vulgaris a piece of software
because it's been forced on people but
quod suus 'iam coactus est autem populus
you know and you want your iTunes
nosti, et quaeris tibi iTunes
library but that can always be you know
sed quod semper erit bibliotheca non scitis
something that you can migrate over to
quod aliquid potest esse in ratione commeant
linux care I can't argue essential
Linux possum curam ne ultra loquaris essential
because of the show I I'll beat you
Et ostendit mihi propter te beat
every time no we're not arguing but I'm
nullus arguere nos non sum sed ego omni tempore
just saying thanks Heather get out she
dicentes gratias agimus Heather ut sicut de illa
agrees about the max no I think what
quod puto non congruit de max
we're experiencing what we're seeing is
erant autem cum erant 'patiendi quod
a transition to high quality computing
altum, transeundum ad faciles qualis computing
that is affordable and it's kill an
ut suus 'gravida esse interficere
apple why are they bringing out the new
quare sunt pomum novus educturus
iPad minis and the cheaper I phones that
leo id quod deterius est nimis, et quod non phones
are made of plastic because they're
quia fiunt a plastic es
realizing that there's a market that is
et nesciebat quia verum est, quod illic 'a foro
HUGE that they are not tapped into and
Quod latere non possint INGENS
it's damaging them as far as I'm
suus 'tantopere nocent vitaeque eos usque ad me
concerned because that's never what
quia id quod non agitur ut '
Apple was Apple was always the high-end
Lacus Lacus autem erat summus finem semper
hardware they were always the the
et erant semper in odio
rock-solid architecture they switch to
ut mutes rationem tuam petram-solidum architectura
Intel that's fine but now they're this
Intel quod nunc denique est ut sis
same
eandem
thing as all these pc's because they're
eo quod est omnibus haerent PC
running the same hardware just different
currit eadem hardware alia iusta
software so stick linux on it sell it in
linux software ut in ea vendere inhaero per eam
the store it's a thousand dollars
centena copia suus
cheaper I'm all there moving on stop
ego movere ad esse vilis omnes subsisto
whoa check out the chair it looks like
Heus reprehendo sicco is vultus amo sella
Captain Kirk's yeah yeah every cool all
Captain Kirk refrigescant omnia in omnibus yeah yeah
right Red Sea entertainment has just
Mare Rubrum iusti recta est entertainment
launched a tremor FX home using the same
uti eodem BCI tremor launched in domum suam
technology found in select high tech
technology in altum tech selectos
movie theaters course they have
habent quidem cinematographica
pulsating actuators embedded in a chair
sonoris pulsatis actuators embedded in sella
which are triggered by the sounds from
quae de sonis Urguet
movies or video games the seat works
video movies vel ludos sedem opera
yeah the seat works with any home
Yeah operatur ulla cathedra
theater system using a wireless
uti a wireless ratio theatrum
transmitter plugged into an HDMI out
inplenda est transfusor in theatre
port on the receiver depending on the
Portus fretus in die ponderator
sounds pitch you feel vibrations in
Vibrationes pice sentis for-
different locations for example the bass
diversis locis exempli gratia bass
sounds like a big booming explosions
sonat sicut magnus magno explosiones
either felt lower and then tiny little
modico deinde exigua vel animo
gun fires are felt higher up like many
qualia altius ignes sensit gun
high-end home theater components this
domum theatrum components quod summus finis
technology doesn't come cheap of course
Lorem vilis sane non
a forger set equipped with tremor FX
Cornelium Cossum et tremor armato set BCI
starts at only twenty thousand dollars
incipit centena viginti milia
you can buy a small car with fork chairs
vos can emere parva currus cum furca chairs
in it that vibrates when you rev the
Cum autem micat inibi rev
engine is for this licked massage chairs
hoc est, engine lingebant ulcera massage chairs
no it's just a vibrating the music comfy
suus 'iustus a musica levamentum nullus circum collum erigunt,
you're watching the Chipmunks and based
vos spectant et secundum Chipmunks
on what I'm hearing here it just
Quid ego hic in auditu iustus
resonated in your head well I when I was
resonated cum essem et ego in tam capitis
a teenager you just watched Jurassic
custodientes vos teenager Jurassic
Park though and it's like boom boom boom
Park quamquam suus 'sicut boom et BUTIO boom
and then you're just is like a massage
et tu iustus est sicut massage
that's true but I went to the thrift
quod verum est, sed ibam ad exhortandam parsimoniam sustinen
store as a team oh cuz that's what you
congregem cum a team ut 'quid, o cuz
do you got it you got to survive and I
et vos got suus surrexit et superesse, et
got myself a little pullout couch thing
re autem ipsa a lectus Pullout
okay it was clean Danis cool I got
quia frigus erat, et mundus ego got bene Danis
underneath it and I stuck to big old 12
submota senex et magna adhæsit in XII
inch subwoofers and I ran those into an
et cucurrit ad illos in inch subwoofers
axiom sub output mm-hmm and it's got a
illud sub-output mm hmm, et suus 'got a
crossover and everything and I had that
et omnia quæ habebat, et crossover
for twelve dollars and you're telling me
Duodecim dollariis constiterunt, et quia vera erant mihi
its twenty thousand dollars for four
viginti quattuor milia pupa
chairs it looks leather it's pleather I
Et spectat zonam chairs suus 'pleather
mean come on
intelliguntur venit
who knows and is that thing on mine was
et qui scit aliquid in eo quod est meum
vinyl what's that goal thing looks like
quod propositum est, ut vultus amo suus 'Vinyl
this is the cup holder it looks like
hic calix novum aeternumque possessor is vultus amo
with maybe like a side table with an LED
fortasse ex parte tamquam in tabella DUXERIT
cup holder or maybe it's like oral who
maybe suus 'tanquam possessor, vel qui calicem oris
knows but couldn't you just make it
sed non scit, non solum ea faciunt
yourself with a couple of subs no get
ut nec tibi cum duobus subs
that cup holder you don't get the cup
quia non accipere calicem de possessor poculum
holder but you could for another 499
sed quia se poterat possessor CDXCIX
with LED lights with LED lights hey I
et dixi heu DUXERIT luminaria et luminaria DUXERIT
got one more story for you you're gonna
got fabulam tibi unum et amet
love this Krista hmm gaming consoles are
hmm hoc Imagines fautorum ex forumque aleatoruml solatur amore sunt,
doomed yes is awesome check it out
Sic terror look acribus
yesterday valve announced they are
heri nuntiatum sunt valvae
releasing steam OS it's a free
releasing vapor OS suus 'libera
linux-based operating system designed
Linux operating ratio fundatur disposito
for the TV and the living room steamos
et ad TV exedra steamos
promises in-home streaming of your Steam
domi tuae promittit vapor infusum
games right to your TV streaming music
ius vestri TV ludos musica streaming
and video and the family sharing
et de cognatione sharing and videos
features that we talked about last week
features ut nos loquebatur de ultima septimana
that allow everyone in the family all
quod unicuique omni familia
the devices to be able to share the
et inventa sunt participes esse poterit
games steamos is going to be available
steamos ludos praesto est iens futurus
soon as a free download and also going
primum ire et libera download
to be offering it as a freely licensed
ut offering ut plura discas
of licensable operating system for
licensable of operating ratio est
manufacturers so they can include it in
ita non includit in se manufacturers
their console this is the first of three
quorum primum est consolatorium trium
big announcements this week from valve
announcements magna ex hac septimana valvae
they are going to be doing the next
deinde facere sint
announcement tomorrow so check cat five
Cras felis quinque reprimendam adeo nuntiatam
dot TV / valve bookmark that the
dat TV / valvae ut bookmark
announcement is going to happen the
nuntiantes in futurum
countdown is there you'll be able to
countdown est ut tibi erit
follow the developments but with this I
Hoc autem sequeretur explicationibus
think one of the announcements that
unum esse pronuntiavit
we're going to see hypothetical
hoc putative erant 'iens ut videre
situation could it be a steam box could
vapor situ potest fieri poterat arca archa
they be bringing out their own gaming
non potest producere sua ludum
console there are two more announcements
nuntiata sunt duo consolantur
happening this week folks cat five dot
fieri id cat septimana quinque dat folks
TV / valve citing days he looks like oh
TV / dies cum adhibet testimonia valvae vultus amo O
yeah you guys are interested eating at
yeah comedere vos guys es interested in
the full stores at category five dot TV
stores plenam dat TV quinque ad genus
/ newsroom the category five TVs
/ TV quinque NEWSROOM genus
newsroom is researched by roy w dash
Latin newsroom Roy per hoc euenit de latibulis surrexissent
with contributions from our community of
in conventu nostro de contributionibus
viewers and if you have a new store you
et si tibi copia novum viewers
think is worthy of on-air mentioned you
est dignum putas on-aer mentio incidit,
can email us at news room at category 5
locus nobis ad nuntium possunt email ad genus V
TV from the category 5 TV news room i'm
A TV ad cubiculum Im 'genus V TV News
chris 12 thanks Krista this is category
XII Chris Imagines fautorum ex hoc ago genus
5 technology TV our website is triple w
V technology TV nostrum website Latin triplum
category five dot TV so nice to have you
TV et dat tibi bellum ut in genus quinque
here and I hope you're enjoying yourself
Spero vos erant 'hic et frui te
tonight all right back to our feature
iure nostro hodie pluma
we're looking at how to create a PHP
erant 'vultus procul quam creare PHP
script to do everything that we're doing
erant autem facientes faciemus omne verbum quod scriptum est
all right check this out back to my
recte hoc reprehendo referte
script so we've learned to execute PHP
ita scriptum facere didici PHP
code now what we want to do is we
signum ergo nobis quid vis ut faciam tibi est,
actually want to get this list imagine
vere volo impetro imaginari quod album
not having to go copy link location I've
non habentem ire exemplum locus Link quia commune aut inmundum
only got five files imagine if you had a
si modo possedi quinque habebat imaginari files
hundred imagine if you had 50 even it
quod si eosdem centum L ipsa
would just be time consuming and
iustus exsisto perussi et in hoc tempore
annoying that's why I like to automate
ideo libenter molestum automate
things when I program I love automation
cum res progressio amo Automation
so we're going to use curl which I've
sic erant 'iens ut, quae Crispum quia commune aut inmundum
already installed we're going to create
iam installed erant 'iens creo
a curl variable here we're gonna just in
Nunc sit amet justo in Crispum variabilis
it curl just like that I'm going to post
Crispum et ut iustus amo Im 'iens post
all this code for you on the show notes
Haec tibi spectaculum notis code
for episode number 314 if you want to
res ad CCCXIV numerum si vis
follow along I'm going to try to do this
Ego hanc sequuntur conantur
without any doing this long hand I'm
sine hac autem facientes longo me manum tuam
going to try to do it without any syntax
facere nullo molior syntaxis
errors we'll see what we can do and to
quod youll 'animadverto errorem facere potest et
set up the options for curl so this is
ideo bene sic statuit Crispum
where we're going to tell it the URL
ubi erant 'iens ad eum domicilio
which we're going with demo cat5 TV / 0
quæ erant cum eo demo CAT5 TV / 0
16 and we're going to actually load from
XVI: et erant 'iens ut vere ex load
that site
quod situm
bear with me as I get through my options
sustineretis modi cum quid adepto quod per options
to load an external site through curl
onerare situs est externum, per Crispum
and what this is going to do notice
et quod haec sit facturus notitiam
we're not using file or file get
vel lima impetro file erant 'non usura
contents because if we did that we might
quia virtute continet quod fecimus
run into security violations that would
si pignus violationes, quae in current
break the script and make it so that it
ita ut conteram enim audire et facere
doesn't work because that can often be a
qui non operatur, quia saepe esse
security exploit so we're going to avoid
sic erant 'iens ut ne credam securitatis
that all together we're going to use
omnes simul erant 'iens ut uti,
curl to get around it okay so I've got
Ego got circa ad eam, ut bene Crispum
everything set up now I'm going to
set omnia usque nunc, Im 'iens
actually load my data I'm going to call
Im 'iens appellare mihi data actually load
the string data and we're going to go
linea data, et ad quod erant 'iens
curl exec and we're going to actually
exec Crispum et nos erant 'iens ut actually
execute the command above which is ch so
ut dictum est cap iussum
now well first of all I should close
iam primum omnium claudere
curl close that off the connection here
Crispum claudere off nexu, ut hic,
and now if I print R which is to output
et nunc, si est qui typis R output
the array I'm going to print our data so
ut procer nostrum data et ordinata sum et vado
that should contain the contents of that
id quod continet contenta
Apache script now there it is so that is
Inde nunc est quod scriptum est Apache
actually like a view source of that
qui visu quoque sicut fons
Apache script so those are the links
Et nexus eorum est scriptor Apache
that we want to actually parse so now
ut volunt ad parse et nunc quidem
that we've got that control k to delete
Comperto quod est k potestate delere
a line and then here we go so we're
Sic igitur abeamus hinc nos lineam
going to actually parse that up I'm
Im 'iens ut esse sursum quod parse
going to clean up the code first of all
Ad primum signum mundi
we're going to strip out a bunch of you
de te detrahere iens fasciculum
know if there's anything that we need to
Si illic 'aliquid quod postulo scio
clean up i'm going to call this will go
Im 'iens appellare ad hoc usque emundare
cleaned equals strip tags and then we'll
purgantur tunc puteus 'tags valet habena
just simply clean up the output which
simpliciter tersus sursum quam sicut output
was data and we're going to all met our
et data est iens ad omnia occurrit nobis
a href leave those ones intact now we're
img src = ones integrum relinqueret his nunc sumus
going to do a preg match which is going
par est quae facturus est preg
to use we're going to actually do a
ut erant 'iens ut faceret in actually
little bit of regex here you don't need
modicum aliquantulus of regex non opus est tibi hic
to follow along with me I'm going to
Im 'iens ut sequi una mecum
really quickly type it in as fast as I
typus ut ieiunium quod in re cito
can without making any syntax errors do
nec potest facere sine risu faciunt Syntax
some regex to take an H RAF and create a
etiam om regex ut aliquid creare et RAF
two-part array so with this regex we're
Duo-pars ordinata regex quod sic sumus
going to create an array that stores the
ordinata est ad partum, qui recondit
full link including the a href so that
plenus link Index inter quas et img src =
we can use it for whatever but also just
uti possumus, sed etiam propter quaecumque iusta
the file name
quod lima nomen eius
okay this is gonna be fun it's not as
id est ut suus 'non agnus dei esse bene fun
good regex is never fun folks I am
regex quod bonum amet folks nunquam mihi
kidding okay preg match all this is the
bene est omnibus par est cognati preg
PHP command that we're gonna do and here
PHP, et mandatum, quod sumus agnus dei hic facit
we go I can't talk through this Krista
Imagines fautorum, per quod itur Non possum loqui
talk amongst yourself amongst myself oh
quis apud me apud te loquor
well there's people listening it's got
illic 'got suus' etiam audire homines
to be interested I guess you know
EGO coniecto ut scitis sit amet
whatever I want about robbery now cuz he
Volo autem de rapinis et quocunque cuz
is concentrating so hard yeah come on
Yeah intenta tantopere venire
carrot where are you there we go alright
CAROTA imus, quo nihil Licuit
href yeah okay so and then we need a
href yeah ita et bene sit nobis necesse
carrot and a slash yeah alright we're
CAROTA et a VULNUS yeah licet sumus
just kind of discussing in the chat room
Sicut in genere disputando chat
here all the extra features that chair
hie omnes, qui extra features sella
must have I think it would be awesome in
necesse est ut puto in hoc horribilis
order to be twenty thousand dollars yeah
Ut memini centena milia
I'll say that's yeah let's present
Et dicunt quod in praesenti puncto yeah
discussion is there a toilet we think it
non enim puto esse disputationem latrina
should come with a toilet definitely
CULTUS cum venerit certus
cooler toaster album small butler follow
Frena parum album sequitur alterum frigidiorem
ensberg yeah this should output two
si duo ista memini ensberg output
matches alright haven't done any syntax
nec aliquid licet matches syntaxis
errors there we go okay so I've created
Ego risu digna sunt et creata bene imus,
an array with regex that the first array
et direxerunt aciem primam regex
is the actual a href that it's found the
et ipsa div inventus sit qui suus '
second array is just the file names that
secundo ordinata est tabella, quae nomina
is found within the HR f okay so that's
HR inventus est in f, ut suus 'okay
what we've done with regex there through
cum feceris quod ibidem regex
a preg match all now what I want to do
preg par sit universis et nunc quid vis ut faciam tibi
is we want to actually get out I just
Nos volo ut vere adepto iustus est de me
want the data that I need so we're gonna
et volo ut notitia nos postulo ut amet
use a for each we know that this is an
per hanc enim scimus, quae in usu est
array and if it's not who cares we don't
ordinata et si non possumus facere, qui non curat
need to do an if is array we don't need
si feceris quod postulo, est non necesse habemus ordinata
to do any of that stuff we're just going
ut faciam omnem supellectilem illius erant 'iustus vado
to go for each because we don't really
quia non vere ire in invicem
need all the air handlers and stuff I'd
omne opus ex aere et supellectilem tracto mallem
love to teach you all that but ok so
Bene autem ut docerem te quae amant
we're going to for each matches as
erant 'iens pro invicem ut aequet
dollar sign filename so what we're doing
Quid ergo agis name pupa signum
is we're doing a loop through the array
erant autem facientes in is ordinata per loop
called matches which I just showed you
sicut dicitur quod par ostendit vobis
and if I go echo dollar sign file name
si pupa signum et resonare ut lima nomen eius
dot PHP eol which is an end of line
apicem versus finem PHP est eol
which is a carriage return output in
quod est in raeda reditus output
terminal and I run that you'll just get
quod youll 'adepto iustus terminalibus curro
a ray to string conversion file name as
ray quod nomen lima per conversionem ad filum
an array is it well beg your pardon it
peto ut ignoscas respondit exercitu
should be I should be looping through
ut per essem looping
notice matches is a two-part array so
par est ut duos notitiam partim ordinata
matches i should actually before
Matches i ut prius actually
reaching through matches one that's why
qui per causam perveniendi compositus
it's giving me an array air okay so if i
Unde si bene ordinatis aeris mihi eam
run that now you'll see a list of the
nunc currere, quod youll 'animadverto a album de
the actual file names okay so we've got
ipsam tam bene lima nomen Comperto
the ability to echo out the file name so
et quod facultatem refero sicco lima nomen eius
now we want to actually do something
si autem vis ad aliquid in actu,
with that so we know that we want to use
et cum hoc scimus, nos volo utor
W get to get that file so let's just
Ut W illud lima ut ut lets 'iustus
create an output string and we're going
partum an output filum et nos erant 'iens
to go dot equals so that we're appending
ad apicem erant paria et appending
to an existing string which we're going
quam ad filum existentium erant 'iens
to create right here dollar sign output
ut creare hic pupa signum output
equals just an empty string okay we
Gloria nostra inanis est aequalis purus
can't depend to a string that isn't
filo pendere non potest esse
created otherwise you can create errors
aliter creavit te potest creare error
in our PHP log because it's going to
PHP lignum quod in futurum
tell us that the the variable doesn't
nos, dico quod non est variabilis
actually exist to append to in not as
ut in rerum natura non appendamus
easy to understand terms it does that so
facile ut secundum ipsum
we're going to go w get just like we did
Latin erant 'iens ad nos, ut sicut fecerunt
dash dash limit dash rate equals 200 k
rate de latibulis surrexissent de latibulis surrexissent de latibulis surrexissent terminum dividuntur, CC k
HTTP colon slash slash demo cat five dot
HTTP colonia VULNUS VULNUS demo cattus dat quinque,
TV / 0 16 / ' dot dollar sign file name
TV / 0 XVI / 'pupa signum dat lima nomen tuum
is the file name that we have and that
quod nomen lima quod nos habere, et
is going to add the file name to the end
Ad hoc addere tabella nomen eius usque ad finem
of that line so now I want to go dash 0
ne unquam offendas ad lineam ab, ita nunc vis 0
and we're going to output to let's just
et nos erant 'iens ut lets' iustus output
do dollar sign filename so that's going
pupa ut faciam signa name deferretur
to save it to the local folder as the
ut eam ad loci folder
file name I don't have to go through the
lima ut per nomen non habent
one two three four and then space
Tribus quattuor deinde spatium duo
ampersand is going to multitask it and
ampersand est ad eam et multitask
we need to have a carriage return at the
Nos postulo a raeda reditu in
end of that line when we output it so
fine versus cum ita output
that's what it looks like but we have a
Hoc illud est quod is vultus amo non habemus
problem here because you remember that
quia quaestio hic qui meministis
matches was actually showing us some of
par erat effective demonstraretur aliquid a nobis,
the the stuff here the a href that we
hic autem de supellectilem quae ad img src =
don't want like that ? c equals n so
sicut quod non vis? aequalis igitur c n
that would actually it'll actually try
quod iam actu conantur ipsum
to download that so let's use a very
ut download quod utor a ipsum, ut lets '
very simple STR a STR to determine
str STR statuere amet
whether or not this is a JPEG file what
aut si id non est, quod JPEG lima
that means is to search within a string
significat quod intra est quaerere filum
in case sensitive so if str I str search
si sensitivo sp Si ergo ego VUL quaerere
within a string in case sensitive that
et in sensitivo quam in casu filum
the I stands for if str is TR and its
non enim stat pro suis: et si is TR subsp
haystack needle so we need file name
nobis necesse est nomen file foramen acus transire toto faeneum
first comma and then dot jpg and here we
Hic autor dat jpg comma ante et
can go jpg.jpg jpg because we're doing
jpg.jpg possunt ire discis quod jpg
an N case sensitive search then we're
N causa quaerere in sensitivo ergo sumus
going to add this to output so only if
addere ad hoc tantum, ut output
its a dot jpg file do we actually create
et nos principatu eius pactum A: inpacatum jpg file creo
this output that says W get so now if I
quia haec dicit output W ita ut, si iam
at the end of this go echo dollar sign
signum istud fine vocis pupa
output save that and run my script
scriptor output mea currunt nisi
you'll see that we have all these w get
youll 'animadverto ut adepto omnes isti Latin
lines see that and it's exactly like
est prorsus sicut lineae et videre illam
what we were creating manually but we're
quid partum sunt manually et sumus
actually obtaining these automatically
hi quidem statim obtinendae
through curl and then outputting them so
Crispum et sic per outputting
now how do we execute that well we're
Quid ergo nos sumus, bene exercendum percipiendo annis
going to edit that a little bit further
adhuc paululum, ut iret recensore eget
and let's use simple PHP to append to
et in usu simplex PHP ad appendamus
our output here at the beginning we're
output hic sumus nos in initio
going to go okay first of all you know
bene scis ire primum
what we need to save it as a file here's
nisi quod necesse est ut suus 'a lima hic,
where things get interesting let's go
ubi interesting res ut abeamus
file output contents and we're going to
et nos erant 'iens ut contentis in eodem file output
create a file called PHP output dot sh
php lima dicitur creare output dat sh
remember we're creating an SH file from
memores enim erant partum a lima per SH
within PHP this is cool comma dollar
php pupa carmina intus est frigus
sign output so if I do that now and
si nunc faciam signa output
execute that watch what happens there's
quid ibi faciant excubitores
not going to be any output called
non posse dici output
undefined file output contents up my
Finis output lima tenor meum
mistake file put contents of course
posuit contentis in eodem file errorem sane
doing things on the fly there notice it
Musca enim fallit in rebus
didn't do anything but if I do an LS
si autem facio et quid faciatis non LS
you'll see that there is now a PHP
inde nunc est quod youll 'animadverto a PHP
output SH and if I cat that which is to
et si quod est feles output SH
look at the contents of the file it is
at illa quae in tabella est,
the commands what's it missing there's
quid illic mandavit deesse
no crunchbang okay so we need to have
non opus est tibi ut bene crunchbang
the she bang at the top of that file
Quæ cum bang ad summitatem illius file
we're not going to edit the file let's
erant 'non iens ut emendo lima Sit scriptor
use our PHP script to actually do this
utere nostris, ut vere facere PHP script
so in the file out file put contents
et posuit in page lima sicco lima
there it is ok before output I'm going
Im 'iens illic est ok in conspectu output
to go ' and then she bang bin bash okay
ut et tum CREPITUS bin bene vercundus
dot PHP eol so next line and then output
Mox deinde ut output eol apicem PHP
and then because it's multitasking what
propter quod et multitasking suus
do we need is a dot PHP eol for next
quid enim necesse est punctus in altera col PHP
line and then a dot and wait remember
dein apicem versus meminisse visendum
that weight because if we execute this
quia si hoc facere pondus
everything's going to all cascade and
atque omne futurum Caesar omnibus
happen all at the same time and then
omnia fieri et simul
we're absolutely messed because
quia erant omnino messed
everything is just happening all at once
quae est sicut eventuras esse simul
okay so I'm going to help put that file
quod lima ut Im 'okay ad auxilium posuit
and if all went well I'm going to run
Et si omnia recte agerentur erga Im 'iens currunt
dot slash test dot PHP it executed no
exacuere vade test apicem apicem PHP non sit supplicium
errors there's the file cat PHP output
php lima est ibi cattus errores output
SH and you'll see that it starts with a
Et quod youll 'animadverto incipit cum a SH
she bang bin bash and it knows what it
non enim novit quod CREPITUS bash et bin
is that it's supposed to run and there's
quod suus 'supponitur currere atque illic'
the weight which doesn't have a carriage
non pondere currum
return after it so it immediately
ideo statim post reditum
returns here but that's fine okay so now
et nunc autem hic refert okay ut 'bysso
let's create a new script we're going to
partum a novus scriptor erant 'iens ut lets'
call this one final dot sh and this is
idemque hoc dat hanc sh
what's going to actually make all the
quod suus 'iens ad hoc passiva ut omnis
magic happen in batch this is a bash
Pagina massa sit amet accidere
script right so we're going to first
sic erant 'iens ut ante dextra scriptor
we're going to execute our PHP script
faciendam nostram scriptionem iens PHP
what did I call that one again test dot
quod iterum experiri quid dicam dot
PHP
PHP
test dot PHP so once that's executed we
php ut suus 'quod dat test aliquando nobis supplicium
know that it has a weight command in it
scitis quod in ea habet pondus imperium
so that's fine so test dot PHP outputs
ita ut suus 'denique test dat outputs PHP
the script which we want to run which is
scriptum est enim quod volo ut run is, qui
PHP output Sh okay if all goes well
Si bene II purus output PHP
let's see I'm going to save that and
nisi ut videamus et Im 'iens
there's one thing that we need to add to
illic 'unus res ut nos postulo ut addere
our test dot PHP here and that is that
hinc est, quod dat amet nostris PHP
right now we're putting a file PHP
php lima ut es nunc, pronuntient,
output SH on our hard drive but what do
Sed quid nobis SH output ferreus coegi
we notice with an LS dash al is that
nos animadverto is cum LS de latibulis surrexissent et al
that script though created is not
quod etsi creata est scriptor
executable it has no executive a bit so
quia non habet partem, sic est exsecutiva exsecutabile
within our PHP file we can actually upon
php lima possumus in nostra super actually
creation of that file we can go exec
creatio autem, ut possimus ire file exec
which is to execute a Bosch command and
Hieronymus et facere quod praeceptum
then apostrophe is not that one because
eo quod tunc non apostrophe
we're not in the bash script when a PHP
sumus in a PHP Cum vercundus scriptor
script and go chmod plus X PHP output Sh
chmod legere poterat ut plus output II X PHP
so now if I run test dot PHP it's
Nunc ergo si test run dat suus 'PHP
created the script if I do an LS dash al
si quid creatum est scriptor LS de latibulis surrexissent et al
you'll see that PHP output SH is
php output est, quod youll 'animadverto SH
executive all ok so now nano our final
Nunc ergo omnes ok exsecutivam Nano supremum nostrum
Sh so now we know that that script is
Sb illud igitur nunc scimus quia scriptum est:
executive all and now madra phi dash
et omnia idola exsecutiva Madra Phi
resize 640 x 360 star jpg save that echo
Paginae nisi stella vocis x DCXL resize CCCLX
done
factum
there we go so now chmod plus x final sh
nunc adeo ibo illuc si x plus chmod ultima sh
and what is that that is our final
Et quid est nostra ultima, quae est,
script it is going to connect out get
scriptum est enim ad coniungere de possidebit
the list from Apache download everything
cum a album download Omnia Apache
asynchronously multitasked then wait and
et sustine asynchronously multitasked
then it's going to modify everything and
ut omnia deinceps mitigare
resize it to a maximum of 640 x 360 Wow
Curabitur id maximum resize DCXL x CCCLX
there it goes that sounds pretty
sonans ibi quidem satis
impressive so all of those things not to
Omnes ad ea dignitas
show you how to do this specific thing
ut ostendam vobis quid est hoc specifica
but really when you understand some of
nisi aliquam rem ex quo intellegis
the underlying concepts you may have to
subiectorum rationem fortasse
watch this Syria this particular episode
haec res Syriae hanc
a few times to to really grasp all of
ut vere cunctis aliquoties percipere
the things recovered i'll certainly post
post haec recuperavit profecto
things that's done just so you know so
Ita factum est ut scitis
you see that when i echoed done at the
Cum autem videritis quaeque geruntur
end it is done and if i open any of
aperite aliquis terminus si fieri
these files you'll see that the file
quod lima youll 'animadverto illis files
size is a maximum of 640 x 360 so that
est maximum mole et de CCCLX x DCXL
one max out at 360 height and so every
Max omnia unum sunt et altitudinem CCCLX
file downloaded and and worked there you
lima vos downloaded atque illuc: et laboraverunt
have it so um Wow yeah there's a lot to
sic illic 'non multus ut in um yeah Wow
cram into an hour I know that it was
Scio quia cram in hora
just go go go hope they enjoyed it and
Habebant et iustus sperare GO
I'm sorry that we didn't get to hear
Paenitet, nos non tantum audire
fewer questions or even two we didn't
paucioribus etiam duas quaestiones vel non sumus
get to chat a whole lot yeah that was
Curabitur id memini adepto multus
his plan was my plan yeah give her an
yeah consilium meum est consilium ejus in eam
easy evening hope you had fun tonight
Facile hac vespera fun spero
folks and get your questions in to us
ac rogationibus tuis adepto folks ad nos
it's live at category five dot TV I'm
Vivamus at TV suus 'genus dat quinque me
going to be hanging around in the chat
iret ut ad chat tentorium circa
room after the show for a little bit if
locus ad spectaculum post paululum si
you want to join us there's category 5
vis iungere V nostrum genus est scriptor
on freenode and we'll certainly say
freenode youll 'certe est et dicere
hello pops an email live at category 5
salve operculum amovet inscriptio an vivat genus in V
TV and let us know what you thought of
Sciunt quid cogitatur et nos in TV
the show and have a fantastic week I
et habent fantastic ostendo sum sabbati
can't believe that our is gone well you
non potest credere quia non tam nostra profecta est,
talked a lot i did my mouth is dry your
ego did mi is sicco os tuum multus loquebatur
hands cries as typing typing typing and
et voces capsas meas capsas typing
I
ego
haven't drank all my water but I made it
Bibebant autem non omne illud aqua
and I had no syntax errors good for you
Syntax pro ignorantia boni et nihil
which is really good I didn't bring any
quod est vere bonum, non aliqua adducere
lollipops gold stars gold star right
lollipops aurea aurea stellarum stella recta
there sorry back of my head next time
iterum caput meum doleo reversus est
next time alright well Sasha dramatis is
Not Est bene licet iterum dramatis
going to be joining us next week don't
'iens ut nobis placet nec deinde septimana
miss out on a very very fun show as we
Super ipsum ut feugiat amet spectaculum
start a season seven happy Anniversary
satus de temporum beatus septem Anniversary
to us seasons six is done and we are now
Nunc tempus est ut sex fiunt
six years old whew I'm 66 have a great
sex annorum LXVI whew me habet magnam
week everybody hey guys Krista thanks
Imagines fautorum ex omnibus gratias agere guys heus octo
for being here my problem you went out
meum non est hic quaestio de intrastis
of me yep nice put it up mm-hmm
nice quod de me yep posuit eum mm hmm,
we hope you enjoy the show category five
Tu speramus frui spectaculum quinque genus
TV broadcasts live from Barrie Ontario
TV broadcasts live from Barrie Ontario
Canada every tuesday at seven pm eastern
Martis per septem omnem Canada post meridiem ad orientem
if you're watching this on demand or
Si vos vigilo is in demanda seu
through cable TV check out the local
Per funem TV loci reprehendo sicco
show times in your area at category five
ad ostendendum genus area quinque vicibus
TB and find out when you can watch live
Et invenietis, cum TB et vigilate possis vivere
and interact in the community chat room
et civitatis gerit mutuam in chat cubiculum
category five is a production of prodigy
quinque productio est genus monstri simile
digital solutions and is licensed under
et digital solutions sit amet
creative commons attribution 2.5 canada
Creative Commons Attribution 2.5 bibendum
we'll see you next time thanks for
ut youll 'animadverto vos iterum gratias agens pro
tuning in
in tuning